<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Christmas Tale, A</name>
   <company>IFC Films</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Comedy</genre>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Arnaud Desplechin</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Arnaud Desplechin</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>France</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Catherine Deneuve</actor>
      <actor>Jean-Paul Roussillon</actor>
      <actor>Anne Consigny</actor>
      <actor>Hippolyte Girardot</actor>
      <actor>Emile Berling</actor>
      <actor>Mathieu Amalric</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>November 14, 2008</release_date>
   <running_time>150</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie is enchanting.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20239813,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A movie that is almost indecently satisfying and at the same time elusive, at once intellectually lofty -- marked by allusions to Emerson, Shakespeare and Seamus Heaney as well as Nietzsche -- and as earthy as the passionate provincial family that is its heart and cosmos and reason for being.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2008/11/14/movies/14tale.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What results is a captivating portrait of the most gorgeously fractious dysfunctional family.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/news/reviews/la-et-christmas14-2008nov14,0,6741239.story</url>
         <critic>Kenneth Turan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Vuillards are not an easy family, and A Christmas Tale is not an easy movie. But by the end, what Desplechin has given us -- in his own inexplicable way, which is sometimes meandering and sometimes piercingly direct, and sometimes both at once -- is a benediction.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2008/11/14/christmas_tale/</url>
         <critic>Stephanie Zacharek</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Darkly hilarious, brilliantly acted.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/11142008/entertainment/movies/family__friends_or_faux_138565.htm</url>
         <critic>Lou Lumenick</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Desplechin's films are great, chaotic, unsettling fun. This one's scored, elegantly, to a mixture of standards and classics and original music by Gregoire Hetzel.</snippet>
         <url>http://chicago.metromix.com/movies/movie_review/movie-review-a-christmas/780971/content</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The most emotionally rich and cinematically thrilling film I've seen all year, a film that pulses with human life in all its terrible and beautiful irrationality.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/388708_christmas21q.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>With at least nine primary characters and running two and a half hours, it's a big, fat novel of a movie - a domestic epic that fuses bitterness and forgiveness in completely satisfying ways.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=12364</url>
         <critic>Ty Burr</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>At last, a great contemporary holiday movie that's strictly for grown-ups - a holiday movie that really is a moviegoer's holiday from desultory daily fare.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/bal-to.christmas12dec12,0,4244157.story</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Desplechin is an inspired impurist. His Christmas Tale is untidy, overstuffed and delicious: a genuine holiday feast.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newsweek.com/id/169189</url>
         <critic>David Ansen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Density of detail and intensity of experience are the twin distinctions of A Christmas Tale, a long, improbably funny and very beautiful film.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.wsj.com/article/film_review.html</url>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Is A Christmas Tale a masterpiece? Maybe. I have to play with it longer. It's certainly Desplechin's most accessible film, in part because its dysfunctional-family-holiday-reunion genre is so comfy and its palette so warm.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/52016/index1.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A heady plum pudding of a movie--studded with outsized performances and drenched in cinematic brio. The concoction is over-rich, yet irresistible.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/2008-11-12/film/desplechin-s-a-christmas-tale-is-the-gift-this-season-needs/</url>
         <critic>J. Hoberman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Vuillards, however fractured, know one another's rhythms and rituals, and Desplechin knows just how to convey them in the subtlest of ways.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A715666</url>
         <critic>Kimberley Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>For long stretches A Christmas Tale seems to be going nowhere in particular and using a lot of dialogue to do so. These are not boring stretches. The movie is 151 minutes long and doesn't feel especially lengthy. The actors are individually good. They work together to feel like a family.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20081119/REVIEWS/811199992</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Roiling with laughter, tears, drunken confessions, revelatory soliloquies, pain, sorrow, hospital visits, and various kinds of love, A Christmas Tale is a smart, sprawling, and sublimely entertaining feast.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/inquirer/columnists/steven_rea/20081120_A_Christmas_Tale.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Dark secrets are unlocked, words draw more blood than punches, and Desplechin turns one family into a universe that resembles life as a startling work of art.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.rollingstone.com/reviews/movie/20774538/review/24199363/a_christmas_tale</url>
         <critic>Peter Travers</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though overly self-conscious, this "Tale" is nonetheless wry, observant and frequently heartbreaking. It's also bound to make you feel better about your own holiday plans.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2008/11/14/2008-11-14_movies_opening_this_weekend_a_christmas_.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Even though it's pretentious and overlong, A Christmas Tale is still maddeningly engaging, thanks in large part to its attractive and gifted cast.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/gog/movies/a-christmas-tale,1152844.html</url>
         <critic>Ann Hornaday</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It sure ain't the Christmas of Dickens's imaginings. Dysfunctional overachievers all, the Vuillards are a family bizarre enough to make the Royal Tenenbaums look like candidates for a Hallmark card.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/RTGAM.20081127.wnoel1128/BNStory/Entertainment/home</url>
         <critic>Rick Groen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>With Desplechin, it doesn't ever feel as though he's straining to show us things. It's more like we're just hanging out. We're in this house, and by some strange coincidence, every time we turn around, something interesting is happening.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2008/11/20/DDB2147SBB.DTL</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's the definition of a film meant to be admired more than loved, but Desplechin's fierce intelligence and uncompromising sense of character come through, as does some of the sharp wit and stylistic flourishes left over from his last film, 2004's "Kings And Queen."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/a_christmas_tale</url>
         <critic>Scott Tobias</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film's success or failure depends almost entirely on a viewer's ability to relate to and become involved in the lives of the characters. We are with them for less than a week and, during that short time, we come to understand the lifetime of hurt and misunderstanding that stands between them.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.reelviews.net/php_review_template.php?identifier=1393</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If feuds, drunken outbursts and thoughtless bed-hopping sound like fun, then A Christmas Tale is a hoot. Some wry humor runs through the course of the overly long saga. But there's not enough dark wit to mitigate the tedium and pretentiousness.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.usatoday.com/life/movies/reviews/2008-11-13-christmas-tale_N.htm</url>
         <critic>Claudia Puig</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It seemed to me as I left the theater that A Christmas Tale was a little too jumpy for its own good, with too many characters and plot points hastily interwoven. But I've come think that it is faithful to its essential purpose, which is to disprove the Tolstoyan dictum that unhappy families are each miserable in their own ways.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.time.com/time/arts/article/0,8599,1859016,00.html</url>
         <critic>Richard Schickel</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Watching A Christmas Tale, with its bursts of old movies, dregs of empty bottles, lines from books, and fragments of half-forgotten conversations, is like getting to know a family other than your own by leafing through its scrapbooks and laughing at its photograph albums, while it bickers in the next room over stuff you may never understand.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/cinema/2008/11/24/081124crci_cinema_lane</url>
         <critic>Anthony Lane</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Despite the name recognition of such actors as Catherine Deneuve and Mathieu Amalric, foreign audiences might be deterred by the movie's 143-minute length and the profusion of characters and interwoven story lines.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/film/reviews/article_display.jsp?rid=11087</url>
         <critic>Bernard Besserglik</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Their endless groupings and regroupings, their brief encounters and power struggles are framed by an armory of cinematic devices that will be familiar to any Desplechin devotee.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/2008-11-13/film-tv/fall-film-a-christmas-tale/</url>
         <critic>Ella Taylor</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Two-and-a-half hours of family bickering, bantering, and pummeling can be draining for the viewer, particularly when many of the characters are easy to dislike.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=11433</url>
         <critic>Stina Chyn</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Largely thanks to the snappy editing, short scenes and a strong cast led by a matronly Deveuve and Amalric's enjoyable perf as the black sheep of the family, A Christmas Tale never devolves into a tedious two-and-a-half hours of self-examination. But it also never goes very far, either.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117937159.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1&amp;query=a+christmas+tale</url>
         <critic>Derek Elley</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>I'd be more inclined to call this French dysfunctional family epic gabby and preeningly self-indulgent – in a word, annoying.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2008/1115/p25s03-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Characters occasionally address the camera, which helps disentangle the competing story lines of madness, adultery, and betrayal.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/33616_CHRISTMAS_TALE.html</url>
         <critic>Andrea Gronvall</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>