<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Clean</name>
   <company>Palm Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Olivier Assayas</author>
      <author>Malachy Martin</author>
      <author>Sarah Perry</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Olivier Assayas</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>CanadaFranceUK</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Maggie Cheung</actor>
      <actor>Mary Moulds</actor>
      <actor>Nick Nolte</actor>
      <actor>Béatrice Dalle</actor>
      <actor>Jeanne Balibar</actor>
      <actor>Don McKellar</actor>
      <actor>Martha Henry</actor>
      <actor>James Johnston</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>August 12, 2005</release_date>
   <running_time>110</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Can a misguided adult start afresh with a new set of values and priorities? This ambitious drama, directed by one of France's most resourceful filmmakers, explores that crucial question in depth and detail.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2005/0812/p14s01-almo.html</url>
         <critic>David Sterritt</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A superb effort by a first-rank director, and manna from heaven for Cheung fans.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/article.asp?section_id=2&amp;article_id=2771</url>
         <critic>Glenn Kenny</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Cheung gives a revelatory performance.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.tvguide.com/newsearch/detail.aspx?id=46899&amp;sourcetype=m&amp;progseriesparentid=0&amp;tvobjectid=0&amp;keyword=&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Cheung is one of the finest actresses working today, an expressive, lustrous beauty capable of plumbing a boundless range of emotional hues. This is the greatest performance she's given to date.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2006/04/28/clean/index.html</url>
         <critic>Stephanie Zacharek</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Beautifully shot and cut, written with a visceral aversion to cliche, deftly skirting sentimentality, sensationalism and simplicity, it continually surprises, engages and satisfies. For a small, unheralded film, it's a knockout.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1150928719279780.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>Shawn Levy</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>One of the most emotionally honest movies about drug addiction ever made.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A369721</url>
         <critic>Marjorie Baumgarten</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Emily is played by Maggie Cheung with such intense desperation that she won the best actress award at Cannes 2004.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20060622/REVIEWS/60620002</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Clean, director Olivier Assayas' spellbinding study of a junkie trying to get her life in order so she can reclaim custody of her child, avoids the pitfalls, brilliantly.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/mld/philly/entertainment/movies/14933365.htm</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Nolte brings this movie a piece of his heart, and grants us peace.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/bal-to.clean16jun16,0,4743080.story?coll=bal-artslife-movies</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The emotional truthfulness of Clean enters into our bloodstreams with its muted vigor, and we find ourselves getting hooked by this tale of getting unhooked.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film/clean-and-sober/13544/</url>
         <critic>Scott Foundas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Clean is one of those movies that's slightly off the mark in ways that are hard to put a finger on, but it is shot so soulfully and features such beautiful performances that it's easy to forgive the occasional false note.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-clean19may19,0,6039719.story</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Albrecht brings out a side of Mr. Nolte rarely seen on the screen, and he gives a deep and touching portrayal of a haggard, beleaguered older man.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2006/04/28/movies/28clea.html</url>
         <critic>Stephen Holden</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Not your average divorce gift: Clean's writer-director Olivier Assayas created the role of recovering rock-world druggie Emily Wang for his ex-wife, art-house/action-pic royalty Maggie Cheung (In the Mood for Love).</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/review/movie/0,6115,1184985_1_0_,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Cheung and Nick Nolte seem unlikely co-stars, but co-star they do in Clean, giving gritty performances under the direction of Frenchman Olivier Assayas.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/movies/67691.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>When these two powerhouse performers come together, a rather predictable tale ignites with surprising force.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/412761p-348937c.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film gets its distinction from the performances by Cheung and Nolte, whose scenes together are suffused with loss and unexpected mutual compassion.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/47866</url>
         <critic>Scott Tobias</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Clean has the same mixture of human tenderness and borderline-silly Eurochic that marks Wenders films like "Until the End of the World."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=8072</url>
         <critic>Ty Burr</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Clean is above all a movie about making peace with uncertainty and doubt and living with the aftershocks of the choices we make. Not the easiest task, but it may be what redeems us in the end.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-060630-movies-review-clean,0,3536842.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Jessica Reaves</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The rough, exposed emotional candor of Cheung's singing voice carries into her performance.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/275866_limited30.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's the moral journey of Nolte's character that is the real story in Clean, but Assayas instead focuses on the manipulative habits of an addict, resulting in a mannered study of narcissism and self-pity.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1104833&amp;lat=200.0&amp;lon=200.0&amp;displaySearchLocation=&amp;nm=1&amp;categories=Movies</url>
         <critic>Ann Hornaday</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Hitting the ground in his ultra-naturalistic mode, Assayas only uncages his star's formidable smile once or twice and never demands our empathy, making Clean a uniquely pungent portrait of dependent personalities and the strain they put on the social weave.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0617,atkinson,72985,20.html</url>
         <critic>Michael Atkinson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's not so much a movie in three acts as three movies stuffed into a single casing, and often showing the strain.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/RTGAM.20050304.wxfilmclean0304/PPVStory/?DENIED=1</url>
         <critic>Rick Groen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Complex but cold tale.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr/reviews/review_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1000515949</url>
         <critic>Ray Bennett</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Maggie Cheung, who was in Assayas's Irma Vep, plays Emily with a semi-detached feeling--observing the role as much as portraying it. The chief pleasure in the picture is Nick Nolte's performance as the boy's paternal grandfather.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tnr.com/doc.mhtml?i=20060522&amp;s=kauffmann052206</url>
         <critic>Stanley Kauffmann</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>An unflinching look at the ravages of substance abuse, and it's also a sobering redemptive tale.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2006/05/26/DDGO2J1KJO1.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>John McMurtrie</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Cheung can't make the woman very interesting in her own right--the most compelling performance here is Nolte's.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/29474_CLEAN.html</url>
         <critic>Jonathan Rosenbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Dramatically pallid and unconvincing. Despite being written for her, the director's "Irma Vep" muse Maggie Cheung seems oddly miscast here and is ill-served by an emotionally underpowered screenplay that rarely gets beneath the surface of the character's problems.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=cannes2004&amp;content=review&amp;reviewid=VE1117923927</url>
         <critic>David Rooney</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Bit of a mediocre drama from writer-director Assayas despite some good turns, not least from Nick Nolte and Beatrice Dalle.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.empireonline.co.uk/site/incinemas/ReviewInFull.asp?FID=11245</url>
         <critic>Alan Morrison</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>true</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>