<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Italian, The</name>
   <company>Sony Pictures Classics</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>FamilyKids</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Andrei Romanov</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Andrei Kravchuk</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Russia</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Kolya Spiridonov</actor>
      <actor>Denis Moiseenko</actor>
      <actor>Sasha Sirotkin</actor>
      <actor>Andrei Yelizarov</actor>
      <actor>Vladimir Shipov</actor>
      <actor>Polina Vorobieva</actor>
      <actor>Olga Shuvalova</actor>
      <actor>Dima Zemlyanko</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>January 19, 2007</release_date>
   <running_time>97</running_time>
   <rating>PG-13</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a carefully and almost classically balanced combination of ingredients, blending dirty-faced realism (so much more damning because it judges and condemns no one) with mystical fable of quest and homecoming.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2007/01/18/btm/index1.html</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Earns its happy ending like few other contemporary dramas concerned with the fate of a child. It puts you through hell for that ending, in fact, hell being modern-day Russia.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-070202-movies-review-italian,0,5316744.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Vanya's journey to find his mom is not easy or picturesque or heartwarming. But it's also never without hope.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/bal-to.italian18may18,0,4623562.story?coll=bal-movies-storyutil</url>
         <critic>Chris Kaltenbach</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Italian is an aesthetic gem, but a moral muddle.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.slate.com/id/2157851/fr/flyout</url>
         <critic>Dana Stevens</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Combining the influences of Italian neorealism with Dickensian melodrama, Andrei Kravchuk's simultaneously tough-minded and sentimental The Italian is as bracing as it is moving.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/film/reviews/article_display.jsp?JSESSIONID=F4fmk26zgY2FH29vG5Tx9SR4tfDLb7npTnPgHLwZ2kf6Px3F2vTv!-5098453&amp;&amp;rid=8688</url>
         <critic>Frank Scheck</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>I was utterly gripped by The Italian. The only problem is that I was rooting for the bad guys.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/26535/</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>There is something slightly magical about the lighting, almost as if this were a fantasy land from which Vanya might actually make an escape. This sense of unreality, of magical thinking and wishing, carries the story and Vanya through a remarkable journey.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2007/01/19/movies/19ital.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>Manohla Dargis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Equal parts "Oliver Twist" and "Pinocchio," Russian director Andrei Kravchuk's fictional hearttugger exposes a troubling real-life practice in contemporary Russia: the buying and selling of abandoned children to rich foreign couples.</snippet>
         <url>http://tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?tvobjectid=285782&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>At heart, The Italian is a Dickensian tale that paints a vivid portrait of post-Glasnost Russia en route to a four-handkerchief ending.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/01192007/entertainment/movies/care_apparent_in_russian_orphan_tale_movies_lou_lumenick.htm</url>
         <critic>Lou Lumenick</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a wish-fulfillment fantasy posing as hard-edged realism.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2007/0119/p14s02-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Before reaching a bittersweet finale that doesn't ring as loudly as it should, The Italian starts to look too much like a neo-realist "Home Alone" sequel, as Spiridonov outwits his pursuers in one scene after another.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/57880</url>
         <critic>Keith Phipps</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The result is a deeply moving experience, alternately funny and sad.</snippet>
         <url>http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/01/26/DDG3PNOCSG1.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Ruthe Stein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's foreign, it's inspiring, it has an adorably resourceful kid; it depicts grinding misery in a land far from West Newton, and it holds out the possibility of clambering over all that misery to attain your dream.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=9264</url>
         <critic>Ty Burr</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's an old-fashioned Soviet road movie, filled with kind souls of the otherwise desperate (and at times predatory) world.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/302077_italian02q.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The result is a picture half sweet, half bitter. Charles Dickens would approve.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20008788,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Italian belongs in group of excellent recent Russian films -- most notably Andrei Zvyagintsev's "The Return" and Boris Khlebnikov and Aleksei Popogrebsky's "Roads to Koktebel" -- that have examined the effects of the country's woes on its youngest and most vulnerable citizens, as well as the problems faced by any child unfortunate enough to have faulty or absent parents. At its best, The Italian conveys this grave issue with admirable clarity and power.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20070202.ITALI02/TPStory/TPEntertainment/Movies/</url>
         <critic>Jason Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A powerful indictment of Russia's illegal adoption industry - and a story of pipsqueak resolve and resilience - The Italian is clear-eyed and tough in its depiction of a corrupt, atrophied social order.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.philly.com/entertainment/ui/philly/movie.html?id=798553&amp;reviewId=22213</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>May be derivative, but it's still engrossing, largely because of its appealing juvenile lead.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/30540_ITALIAN_KRAVCHUCK.html</url>
         <critic>Andrea Gronvall</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A remarkably compelling presence, Spiridonov commands attention without pandering or appealing to pity. In fact, for a 6-year-old, he is possessed of an uncanny poise.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/printedition/calendar/cl-et-italian19jan19,0,3749668.story</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film flirts frequently with sentimentality, falling for it heedlessly at a couple of crucial junctures. Still, the overall style is more astringent than moist, and the hero is a little toughie of endearing tenderness.</snippet>
         <url/>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The juvenile performances are impressive, as they usually are in foreign films, and Spiridonov handles some grueling material with impressive maturity. But the movie comes undone with an abrupt and preposterous finale.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1172093112321250.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>Marc Mohan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Other than the unsatisfactory ending, however, there's much that is commendable in the The Italian, not the least of which are its social criticisms of the buying and selling of children through the adoption businesses currently thriving in Russia and neighboring eastern European countries. In some respects, unfortunately, not much has changed since the world was introduced to little Oliver Twist nearly two centuries ago.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A455832</url>
         <critic>Steve Davis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>There are too many familiar faces in this story, from kindhearted whores to street-urchin bullies. But even if circumstances edge toward the unlikely, Kravchuk and Spiridonov make an effective team, exploring the realities that lead to so much heartbreak for so many children.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/489882p-412524c.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The depiction of everyday life at the orphanage is far more compelling than Vanya's personal quest. It's unfortunate that once the Italian hits the road, The Italian loses its way.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/moviereviews/3434/the-italian.html</url>
         <critic>Ethan Alter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lured, perhaps, by the promise of international markets, Kravchuk instead opts for routine uplift, and once the heroic journey is set in motion, the rest is ballast.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0703,film,75567,20.html</url>
         <critic>Ella Taylor</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>