<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>King of Kong: A Fistful of Quarters, The</name>
   <company>Picturehouse Entertainment</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Documentary</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author/>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Seth Gordon</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>USA</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Billy Mitchell</actor>
      <actor>Steve Wiebe</actor>
      <actor>Walter Day</actor>
      <actor>Todd Rogers</actor>
      <actor>Steve Sers</actor>
      <actor>Doris Self</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>August 17, 2007</release_date>
   <running_time>79</running_time>
   <rating>PG-13</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's all true--every magical, exhilarating, infuriating, dumbfounding, jaw-dropping second of Gordon's miniature masterpiece.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0733,wilonsky,77508,20.html</url>
         <critic>Robert Wilonsky</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A funny and madly arresting new documentary.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20051855,00.html</url>
         <critic>Owen Gleiberman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It’s not just one of the best documentaries I’ve ever seen, it’s one of the best movies I’ve ever seen. Period.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=9866</url>
         <critic>Pete Vonder Haar</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Gordon's documentary proves better than 90 percent of the manufactured stories out this summer. One can breathe a sigh of relief that it was done right and not cobbled into another bad fictional comedy.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-070824-movies-review-kong,0,5191324.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Scott Schueller</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Gordon's feature directorial debut mostly stops being about video-game obsession and turns into a film about what it takes to make it in America.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/the_king_of_kong_a_fistful_of</url>
         <critic>Keith Phipps</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This film about fierce competition among classic video-game players is a comic action epic in documentary form. It captures fear -- and heroism -- in a handful of dusty video games.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/bal-to.king14sep14,0,1551393.story</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Very entertaining (and doesn’t overstay its welcome) but it’s a little depressing to contemplate.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/36069/index1.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If you don't play at all, you may find yourself enjoying this film more than anyone, because you'll at least get all the laughs with none of the cringing self-recognition.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/moviereviews/4028/king-of-kong-a-fistful-of-quarters.html</url>
         <critic>Eric Alt</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Like "Air Guitar Nation," the stranger-than-fiction cast of characters is fascinating, and their high-stakes machinations are nothing short of mind-boggling.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?tvobjectid=289888&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Maitland McDonagh</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Heartbreaking and hilarious.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2007/08/17/2007-08-17_short_takes_more_movies_this_week-1.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A portrait of two different men whose compulsion for Donkey Kong is hilarious.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=10331</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>One of this year's funniest movies -- and its most inspirational sports drama -- is a documentary.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1187740518257010.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>M. E. Russell</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie’s “Rocky” formula proves irresistible anyway; unsurprisingly, New Line has commissioned Mr. Gordon to remake this story with actors.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2007/08/17/movies/17kong.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>Matt Zoller Seitz</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It may seem overblown when one of the gamers calls Donkey Kong a metaphor for life, but The King of Kong is just that -- a reminder of how we all have to prove ourselves to others, and the extent to which the odds are often stacked against outsiders and newcomers.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film/the-king-of-kongs-rival-arcade-gamers/17044/</url>
         <critic>Luke Y. Thompson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Ultimately Gordon's movie becomes both a hilarious story about an unbelievable collection of arrested-teenage morons and, yes, an inspiring fable of persistence and redemption. I haven't mentioned this movie's fabulous addition to the English language yet, so here it is: the verb "to chumpatize."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2007/08/16/btm/index2.html</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Obsession creates its own fascination, and never more so than in King of Kong, a sprightly new documentary that's as compulsively watchable as the vintage video game it focuses on is addictive.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-kong17aug17,0,3097459.story?coll=cl-mreview</url>
         <critic>Kenneth Turan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Pure, goofy fun.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A523931</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Not since "300" have I seen such manly mano-a-mano-ing as the iron clash of wills in the docu mentary King of Kong: A Fistful of Quarters.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/08172007/entertainment/movies/gamers_got_arcade_fire_movies_kyle_smith.htm</url>
         <critic>Kyle Smith</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A documentary that is beyond strange, follows two arch-enemies in their grim, long-term rivalry, which involves way more time than any human lifetime should devote to Donkey Kong.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20070823/REVIEWS/70817011</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Who would have guessed that a documentary about gamers obsessed with scoring a world record at Donkey Kong would not only be roaringly funny but serve as a metaphor for the decline of Western civilization?</snippet>
         <url>http://www.rollingstone.com/reviews/movie/14137645/review/15807945/the_king_of_kong</url>
         <critic>Peter Travers</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>As impressive as it is geeky. Most of the principal characters look like they haven't seen daylight since "Pac-Man Fever" was on the charts.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/08/24/DD4SRO442.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Peter Hartlaub</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A nuanced study in obsession, dedication, manipulation, ethics and how the all-American need to be the best at something -- anything -- can shape a life.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.miamiherald.com/entertainment/movies/story/219881.html</url>
         <critic>Connie Ogle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a depressing little kingdom, even when Gordon tries desperately to goose the drama with the requisite "Eye of the Tiger" riffs and some junior high-level palace intrigue.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1136090&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Ann Hornaday</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>true</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>