<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Let the Right One In</name>
   <company>Magnet Releasing (Magnolia Pictures)</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Horror</genre>
      <genre>Romance</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>John Ajvide Lindqvist</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Tomas Alfredson</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Sweden</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Kare Hedebrant</actor>
      <actor>Lina Leersson</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>October 24, 2008</release_date>
   <running_time>114</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>In the basest of terms, a horror flick. But it's also a spectacularly moving and elegant movie, and to dismiss it into genre-hood, to mentally stuff it into the horror pigeonhole, is to overlook a remarkable film.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/gog/movies/let-the-right-one-in,1152490.html</url>
         <critic>John Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This is one of the real finds of 2008.</snippet>
         <url>http://chicago.metromix.com/movies/movie_review/movie-review-let-the/763148/content</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>At once a devastating, curiously uplifting inhuman drama and a superbly crafted genre exercise, Let The Right One In can stand toe-to-toe with Spirit Of The Beehive, Pan's Labyrinth or Orphee. See it.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?FID=135765</url>
         <critic>Kim Newman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's one of the great horror films of recent years -- and a welcome antidote to the in-your-face sonic assaults that all too often pass for genre fare.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/index.ssf/2008/11/movie_review_let_the_right_one.html</url>
         <critic>M. E. Russell</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The best fairy tales always have so much darkness in them. That's why they resonate so deeply. This is a magnificent film.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=11078</url>
         <critic>Jeremy Knox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Could be summarized as a vampire tween romance, but that cheap and tawdry sum-up does zero justice to the magnificent emotional resonance of this gemlike bloodstone of a film.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A700912</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The beauty of Let the Right One In resides in the way the horror remains grounded in a tragic kind of love.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=12812</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Most contemporary horror films derive shocks from mere torture. Let the Right One In locates most of its fright-power in the needs and confusions of people who are usually overlooked.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/bal-to.let14nov14,0,1889421.story</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The most violent scene is dreamlike, and more direct killings are often seen at an angle or from a distance. The camera placement is thoughtful and effective, never titillating.</snippet>
         <url>http://events.charlotteobserver.com/reviews/show/35245-review-let-the-right-one-in-lat-den-ratte-komma-in-2008</url>
         <critic>Lawrence Toppman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Stick your neck out for this Swedish horror show. It's a winner, full of mirth and malice, plus a young romance you'll never see on the Disney Channel.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.rollingstone.com/reviews/movie/18951763/review/23880463/let_the_right_one_in</url>
         <critic>Peter Travers</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The young actors are powerful in draining roles. We care for them more than they care for themselves. Alfredson's palette is so drained of warm colors that even fresh blood is black.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20081111/REVIEWS/811129995</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Funny, fear-inducing, with periods of voyeuristic gore and an undercurrent of anxiety and dread, Let the Right One In is up there with the bloodsucking classics.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/philly/entertainment/movies/20081114_Vampire_tale_gets_it_frighteningly__Right_.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a little long and dissipates some of its power in an unfocused subplot, but the skewed sensibility of the film is both innocent and feral and offers a smart and satisfying reworking to the familiar genre. An American remake is already in the works.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/387717_limited14.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a sweetly queasy film that suggests the spirit that sustains us, the demons we hide from the world, and the monsters that prey upon us in the dark might all be variations on the same beast.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/let_the_right_one_in</url>
         <critic>Maria Schneider</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a genuine genre vampire picture; and it's Swedish, winter-lit, Bergmanesque.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/51816/index1.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>An ingenious mixture of satire, dead-end suburban realism and gory vampire fantasy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/btm/feature/2008/10/27/right_one/</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A coolly balanced and utterly compelling examination of alienation and love.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/2008-10-22/film/let-the-right-one-in-a-vampire-movie-about-alienation-and-love/</url>
         <critic>Elena Oumano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Let the Right One In unfolds with quiet, masterly assurance.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newsweek.com/id/164500</url>
         <critic>David Ansen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A moody adaptation of the Swedish best-seller about a fateful mortal-vampire romance, Let the Right One In is atypically literate and unexpectedly affecting suspense fare. Complex characters, ominous situations fraught with mortality and the recklessness of youthful ardor create a tense and subtly shaded narrative.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/film/reviews/article_display.jsp?JSESSIONID=drQYJQyFT2TvTdl6QmR0cnv18ZvR8h5v49vy5RtbtHlh6kJ5sq8x!1466636313&amp;&amp;rid=11861</url>
         <critic>Justin Lowe</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Alfredson makes the most of every detail, carefully crafting an atmosphere of haunting alienation. These two lost souls may come together under unusual circumstances, but their connection feels universally human.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2008/10/23/2008-10-23_more_movie_reviews_for_the_weekend_of_oc.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>In this sinister but gorgeous and compelling film by director Tomas Alfredson, being human and acting human don't always go together.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/news/reviews/la-et-rightone24-2008oct24,0,4878617.story</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>There is a remarkable stillness to many of the film's most indelible images, particularly the exteriors, which are so carefully photographed, and without the usual tiresome camera jiggling, as to look almost frozen.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2008/10/24/movies/24righ.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>Manohla Dargis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A remarkably fine and genuinely frightening movie about a teenage vampire.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB122722557296045953.html?mod=article-outset-box</url>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Despite having no previous film experience, Kare Hedebrant and Lina Leandersson give evocative performances as Oskar and Eli, respectively.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/10242008/entertainment/movies/young_blood_for_old_tale_134976.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Let the Right One In is a children's film, but you wouldn't want your child to see it. It's a horror film, but the gruesome splatter is the least of its scares. And it's a love story, but the prepubescent kind where sex is a distant idea and loneliness a shared reality. A wicked trick, a cinematic treat, this is some Halloween offering.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/RTGAM.20081031.wright31/BNStory/Entertainment/home</url>
         <critic>Rick Groen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Strikes a surprising array of notes: scary, sad and hopeful. The director, Tomas Alfredson, does a great job of presenting peril in the film.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2008/11/06/DDLD13VUH2.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Reyhan Harmanci</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Some will classify Let the Right One In as a horror movie, and I suppose that's technically accurate. To me, however, this is much more of a coming-of-age/friendship movie.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.reelviews.net/php_review_template.php?identifier=1391</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Calling to mind the work of Anne Rice and Stephen King, atmospheric adaptation of Swedish author John Ajvide Lindqvist's bestseller is well directed by his countryman Tomas Alfredson ("Four Shades of Brown") and should click with cult and arthouse auds.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=festivals&amp;jump=review&amp;id=2478&amp;reviewid=VE1117936144&amp;cs=1</url>
         <critic>Alissa Simon</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Scandinavian moodiness of the first half gives way to a series of jolting set pieces in the second.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/critic.html#33783</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If random arty blood thrills are your cup of fear, perhaps you'll enjoy Let the Right One In, a Swedish head-scratcher that has a few creepy images but very little holding them together.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20235010,00.html</url>
         <critic>Owen Gleiberman</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>