<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Life Before Her Eyes, The</name>
   <company>Magnolia Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>SuspenseThriller</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Emil Stern</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Vadim Perelman</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>USA</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Uma Thurman</actor>
      <actor>Evan Rachel Wood</actor>
      <actor>Eva Amurri</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>April 18, 2008</release_date>
   <running_time>90</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Emotionally sophisticated, humane and worth talking about for hours.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2008/04/24/DDP210B4VR.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The fact that I didn't understand a film, that its ending can be interpreted at least two ways and maybe three – all likely to be "true" – usually sends me growling in disgust from the theater. But The Life Before Her Eyes has grown on me in memory.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.charlotte.com/151/story/635652.html</url>
         <critic>Lawrence Toppman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Of the two timelines, the one featuring the teenage Diana is more involving than the one featuring the adult version. Both lead actresses give fine performances, but Thurman has less material to work with.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.reelviews.net/movies/l/life_before.html</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though atmospheric and occasionally suspenseful, its gimmickry keeps it from being transcendent.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-life18apr18,0,3429733.story</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Uma Thurman delivers a mesmerizing performance in The Life Before Her Eyes, a film that, once seen and fully digested, exerts the same haunting pull as the shattering events it chronicles.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1147208&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Ann Hornaday</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The best thing about The Life Before Her Eyes, a somber meditation on fate and friendship, is the way it captures the close relationship between two teenage girls.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/inquirer/columnists/steven_rea/20080425_Fateful_tale_undone_in_the_telling.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Boasting two terrific performances by Uma Thurman and Evan Rachel Wood as the adult and teenage versions of the same character.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/film/reviews/article_display.jsp?&amp;rid=9781</url>
         <critic>Michael Rechtshaffen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Life Before Her Eyes is like one of those puzzles. There is something wrong in each scene, and the viewer zeroes in on the elements that don't fit, wondering if there is a purpose behind them.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/360471_life25q.html</url>
         <critic>Bill White</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's sad to see such subtle, wrenchingly emotional work expended on such trifling material.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/life-eyes/review/293464</url>
         <critic>Maitland McDonagh</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Beautiful, horrifying, exasperating and just plain weird.</snippet>
         <url>http://chicago.metromix.com/movies/movie_review/movie-review-the-life/388154/content</url>
         <critic>Sid Smith</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Director Vadim Perelman is big on slo-mo lyrical effects and confusing time shifts, making the movie unnecessarily arty and detracting from what could have been a searing psychological study.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2008/0418/p15s01-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Tidy, predictable, excruciatingly fussy in its details and lacking the tiniest glimmer of humor, The Life Before Her Eyes contradicts the director’s claim in the production notes that the movie “is not a perfectly ordered experience with clear causes and effects.”</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2008/04/18/movies/18life.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>Stephen Holden</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A femme-centric drama about the aftermath of a high school massacre, profoundly confusing "In Bloom" arrives at some very tenuous moral conclusions that might alienate much of its supposed target audience.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117934663.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>John Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Moviegoers may mistake The Life Before Her Eyes for an unduly long L'Oreal commercial featuring softly lit film stars moving languidly with swinging hair through overbearingly premonitory weather.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0816,tracking-5,411829,20.html</url>
         <critic>Ella Taylor</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>While "House of Sand and Fog" remained (somewhat precariously) balanced on the knife-edge that can turn tragedy into bathos, this picture doesn't fare nearly as well, and begins weighing down the viewer with its putative significance only minutes after its opening credits.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/moviereviews/4522/the-life-before-her-eyes.html</url>
         <critic>Glenn Kenny</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>When the big twist is revealed at the end of The Life Before Her Eyes, you might think the only way to appreciate its cleverness is to see the film again. I did that. It didn't help.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=10591</url>
         <critic>Janice Page</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Perelman's follow-up, The Life Before Her Eyes, finds him clumsily trying to outdo M. Night Shyamalan.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/the_life_before_her_eyes</url>
         <critic>Tasha Robinson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Perelman pays such cooing attention to surfaces that our response to violence carries no more importance than our response to the delicate jewelry around the adult Diana's neck.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20192238,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Perelman never overcomes the disjuncture of having two familiar actresses play the same grown character, and despite the endless crosscutting, the two halves settle respectively into ghoulish foreboding and murky psychological drama.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/33073_LIFE_BEFORE_HER_EYES.html</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Perelman eases the transitions between the past and the present with echoing phrases and situations, but they all seem rather pat and contrived. Does he really think that repeated refrains from the Zombies oldie, "She's Not There," won't be a dead (so to speak) giveaway?</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A615539</url>
         <critic>Marjorie Baumgarten</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>An overwrought and patently offensive anti- abortion drama from the director of the accomplished "House of Sand and Fog."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/04182008/entertainment/movies/its_ill_conceived_106961.htm</url>
         <critic>Lou Lumenick</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Confused, morally queasy, self-important mess.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/index.ssf/2008/05/review_surviving_the_life_befo.html</url>
         <critic>Marc Mohan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What this heavy-handed film mainly has to endure is a clunky story structure and an ending that wasn't original when it was seen four decades ago on "The Twilight Zone."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2008/04/18/2008-04-18_uma_thurman_has_a_rocky_road_in_the_life.html</url>
         <critic>Joe Neumaier</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>In a vile-movie competition between Michael Haneke’s "Funny Games" and Vadim Perelman’s The Life Before Her Eyes, Haneke’s film would win--but only because he’s working so much harder to be noxious.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/45985/index1.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Consider this more a consumer warning than a movie review: The Life Before Her Eyes will draw you in, then intrigue you, then bore you, then bewilder you, then make you crazy with its incessant flashbacks and flash forwards, and finally leave you feeling like the victim of a fraud.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB120847468724024687.html</url>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>