<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Lorna&amp;#039;s Silence</name>
   <company>Sony Pictures Classics</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Jean-Pierre Dardenne</author>
      <author>Luc Dardenne</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Jean-Pierre Dardenne</director>
      <director>Luc Dardenne</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Belgium</origin>
      <origin>France</origin>
      <origin>Italy</origin>
      <origin>Germany</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Alban Ukaj</actor>
      <actor>Fabrizio Rongione</actor>
      <actor>Jeremie Renier</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>July 31, 2009</release_date>
   <running_time>105</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>The androgynous Dobroshi is in nearly every scene. She has an exceptional screen presence that brings authority to her portrayal of a woman seeking redemption. As for the Dardennes, they prove yet again that nobody does human frailty the way they do.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/07312009/entertainment/movies/feelings_amid_dealings_182154.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A gritty, deceptively low-key, no-fuss, no-frills movie of consistent originality and surprise in which suspense arises straight up from the heroine's evolving character.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-capsules31-2009jul31,0,6258234.story</url>
         <critic>Kevin Thomas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A stunning study of one desperate woman's conscience.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20294568,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lorna's Silence is engrossing and powerful, which may be just another way of saying it's a film by the Dardenne brothers. If it falls a bit short of the standards of their best work, that is only because it is not quite a masterpiece.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2009/07/31/movies/31lorna.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Renier’s performance is the best thing in the movie, although all the actors, cast partly for their faces, are part of creating this desperate world.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20090812/REVIEWS/908129995</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Dardennes resist the expected cliches: The climactic scenes gather force and purpose and the movie seems headed for a breakthrough of some sort, but then it glides softly and unexpectedly to a halt.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/ae/movies/articles/2009/08/14/lornas_silence_says_all_that_it_needs_to/</url>
         <critic>Ty Burr</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>On a deeper level, the Dardennes' film offers a portrait of a fragile yet determined woman set on making a home for herself in the world, even as that world unravels before her eyes.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/philly/entertainment/movies/20090814_Glimmer_of_hope_among_outcasts.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>By Dardenne standards this plot is pretty pulpy and unconvincing, but I rather enjoyed watching them attempt to twist it into an existentialist pretzel.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2009/0814/p17s02-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lorna's Silence feels like a refinement, even a repetition, of earlier themes. But the brothers are repeating themselves at such a high level that the redundancies are more than welcome.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/articles/lornas-silence,31088/</url>
         <critic>Sam Adams</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Like earlier Dardenne films, Lorna’s Silence is naturalistic, yet this one, beautifully shot in 35 mm film by Alain Marcoen, achieves a poetry of bereftness.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.wsj.com/article/film_review.html</url>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film doesn't pack the same cumulative wallop as the brothers' earlier work, but its low-key artistry, immaculate construction and fine performance by relative newcomer Arta Dobroshi should rouse the usual fest acclaim and arthouse interest.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117937198.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1&amp;query=Lorna%27s+silence</url>
         <critic>Justin Chang</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Something between a love story and a religious morality tale. The hauntingly ambiguous last scene, in which Lorna finds a place of temporary respite from the economic forces that have determined so much of her life, may be the saddest happy ending I've ever seen.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.slate.com/id/2223940/</url>
         <critic>Dana Stevens</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lorna's sudden change of heart is a pointed example of what the Dardenne brothers' movies are all about. Capitalism may seem at times like a raging river, but every day, all over the world, people try to make it flow in the opposite direction.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.chicagoreader.com/chicago/cashing-in-review-of-lornas-silence/Content?oid=1176797</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>While the Dardennes may be moralists, they are also makers of thrillers: The story within Lorna' Silence is built on tiny increments of tantalizing details, meted out in penurious droplets and with chest-tightening tension that suggests that what the brothers wanted to be when they grew up were boa constrictors -- Belgian boas, with degrees in Marxist theory.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/gog/movies/lornas-silence,1156512/critic-review.html#reviewNum1</url>
         <critic>John Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This isn't just another crime story, and it would be misleading to suggest that it has anything to do with stylish gunplay, exhilarating car chases or brutal fistfights.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.stltoday.com/stltoday/entertainment/reviews.nsf/movie/story/A3F08D1EF38FA5D386257625006E493C?OpenDocument</url>
         <critic>Calvin Wilson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Among the Dardennes' more accessible films, despite a drawn-out finale that still doesn't quite satisfy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/index.ssf/2009/09/movie_review_sex_and_dying_in.html</url>
         <critic>Marc Mohan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If you’re new to the Dardennes, Lorna’s Silence will serve as a fine introduction.</snippet>
         <url>http://featuresblogs.chicagotribune.com/talking_pictures/</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Upbeat it ain't, but when the light fades from the final frame, there remains something unusual in the Dardennes canon – the possibility of an escape from futility's clutches, and a reason for hope that might, just might, be more than an illusion.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/arts/lornas-silence/article1266965/</url>
         <critic>Rick Groen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Watching Lorna's attempt to balance self-interest and empathy can be heartbreaking. If Lorna's Silence as a whole doesn't rank among the Dardennes's best, it does follow the money to moments and characters that are unforgettable.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=111380432</url>
         <critic>Mark Jenkins</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Ultimately, this is not one of the Dardennes' masterpieces. They've made a few of those, but the effect of Lorna's Silence is more modest. It leaves the audience with neither a sense of uplift nor devastation, but, rather, with something more akin to intellectual appreciation.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2009/08/06/MVF4194BT6.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Dardennes retain a company of returning players: Jérémie Renier, Fabrizio Rongione, and Olivier Gourmet. Such loyalty is rare and touching.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/2009-07-28/film/the-dardennes-do-what-they-do-in-lorna-s-silence/</url>
         <critic>Nick Pinkerton</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Echoes long after the movie ends.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A832152</url>
         <critic>Marjorie Baumgarten</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It boasts strong acting and a nice dose of suspense.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nola.com/movies/index.ssf/2009/10/post_11.html</url>
         <critic>Mike Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lorna's Silence doesn't work, but it's a beautiful misfire.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.miamiherald.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/story/1215449.html</url>
         <critic>Rene Rodriguez</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>true</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>