<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Orphanage, The</name>
   <company>Picturehouse</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Horror</genre>
      <genre>Mystery</genre>
      <genre>SuspenseThriller</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Sergio G. Sánchez</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Juan Antonio Bayona</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>MexicoSpain</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Belén Rueda</actor>
      <actor>Ferno Cayo</actor>
      <actor>Geraldine Chaplin</actor>
      <actor>Montserrat Carulla</actor>
      <actor>Mabel Rivera</actor>
      <actor>Andrés Gertrúdix</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>December 28, 2007</release_date>
   <running_time>110</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Delivers more goose bumps than anything Hollywood has served up in years – which I hope does not mean that Bayona, a first-time feature director and music video whiz, will be enlisted to direct "Saw V."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2008/0104/p15s01-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Reaches truly terrifying heights as it becomes clear how possible the worst outcome can be. Like "Pan's Labyrinth," this is a movie about children made very much for adults.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1199930113297260.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>Marc Mohan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lures us in with extraordinary subtlety. Keeping sound effects and incidental music to a relative minimum, it builds its suspense almost subliminally. So when something scary or shocking does occur -- deprived of those Hollywood-style cues -- we are truly startled.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1138347&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Desson Thomson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A great horror movie is like a good shrink--and a lot cheaper, too. It purges us through petrification. That horror movie, thankfully, has arrived. It's called The Orphanage," and it is seriously scary.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newsweek.com/id/78173</url>
         <critic>David Ansen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A fastidiously grim ghost story that rattles the bones of the haunted-house genre and finds plenty of fresh (but not too bloody) meat.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=festivals&amp;jump=review&amp;reviewid=VE1117933706&amp;cs=1&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>Justin Chang</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Deliberately aimed at viewers with developed attention spans. It lingers to create atmosphere, a sense of place, a sympathy with the characters, instead of rushing into cheap thrills.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20071227/REVIEWS/712270301</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The acting is uniformly superb, the camera work and set design are haunting, and The Orphanage delivers well-earned tears at its beautiful conclusion. Go see it already.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/12282007/entertainment/movies/scary_home_companion_154653.htm</url>
         <critic>Lou Lumenick</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>By the end, you'll be chilled and disturbed by what you've seen -- and, rare as this is in a horror movie, touched to the heart.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.charlotte.com/entertainment/ui/charlotte/movie.html?id=991927&amp;reviewId=22838&amp;startDate=NEXT7</url>
         <critic>Lawrence Toppman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>While some of the trappings and even some of the plot elements could easily be called unoriginal, Bayona and screenwriter Sergio G. Sánchez arrange them in a fresh way, crafting an emotionally resonant, nerve-jangling experience.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/the_orphanage</url>
         <critic>Noel Murray</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Despite a few bloodcurdling shocks, this handsome Spanish ghost story from producer Guillermo del Toro follows in the suggestive, richly romantic tradition of the old Val Lewton chillers.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/critic.html#32615</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A good old-fashioned horror in the best possible way, this is a beautifully told, terrifying ghost story that lingers with you long after the shivers have stopped.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?FID=135322</url>
         <critic>Olly Richards</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>You exit the cinema in a fever of melancholia, wondering how long it will take you to shed the sensation of alarm. The film is less of a shocker than an adventure in anxiety, testing and twisting some of the classic studies in infantile curiosity.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/cinema/2008/01/14/080114crci_cinema_lane</url>
         <critic>Anthony Lane</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>As Laura, Rueda hits sublime notes of confusion, grief and wrath. She's sympathetic enough to make you root for her and complex enough to get you arguing afterward about whether Laura did anything to deserve all this.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/bal-to.orphanage11jan11,0,4445352.story</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>For those who enjoy ghost stories and are willing to be patient with a movie that gradually unveils its secrets rather than uncovering them all in an orgy of violence and terror, The Orphanage fills a need. The spell it casts early does not evaporate until the epilogue is finished.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.reelviews.net/movies/o/orphanage.html</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>In a genre that has been battered by the cheap grotesqueries of special effects, it is a pleasure to be unsettled by something as simple as an invasive beam of light in the shadows of a haunted house.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/345936_orphanage04q.html</url>
         <critic>Bill White</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>In a season filled with dark-themed films, it stands out as an elegantly mounted, surprisingly humane but terrifying horror thriller well worth seeing.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.usatoday.com/life/movies/reviews/2008-01-03-the-orphanage_N.htm</url>
         <critic>Claudia Puig</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Orphanage gets by on mood and a mournfulness that's not easily soothed. Sadness and loss, it says, are the threads connecting the spirit world and our own, and women, who bring life into the world, understand that far better than men ever will.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=10443</url>
         <critic>Ty Burr</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What distinguishes The Orphanage are some spare but fiendishly well-placed shocks that give the film an extra sense of danger: You can't take comfort with this one assuming you know what lurks around each corner, because you don't. Trust me.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.miamiherald.com/1054/story/373714.html</url>
         <critic>Rene Rodriguez</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Bayona's moves are deft, the atmosphere oozes with anxiety and grief, but the big payoff - like the big payoff in The Sixth Sense, another film The Orphanage has more than a bit in common with - never comes.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/philly/entertainment/movies/20080111_Orphanage_has_some_scares__but_no_terror.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>You're either in the mood to go along with the puzzle pieces or you're not. I'm not usually a puzzle-piece fan myself, not when it's clear that the filmmaker rigs the moves. But I couldn't help but fall for the repurposed real estate, and cheer for the lady strong enough to break through walls when she senses a child is waiting.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20168356,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though the movie has a handful of shots that are downright gross to witness, what makes The Orphanage scary is not what it threatens to show but what it suggests about life.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/12/28/DD1JTUDOG.DTL</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The filmmakers know the tropes of spooky movies: Glowering shadows, squeaking playground equipment, eerie storms and half-glimpsed forms, but the film rests on Rueda's subtle, intense performance, rooted in every half-articulated anxiety that ever gnawed at a parent's brain.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/orphanage/review/291809</url>
         <critic>Maitland McDonagh</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>As in “Pan’s Labyrinth,” The Orphanage relies on a risky blend of clinically realistic horrors and poetic suggestions of an alternate world, one that can be visited, but at a price.</snippet>
         <url>http://chicago.metromix.com/movies/movie_review/movie-review-the-orphanage/271213/content</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>An unexpectedly poignant ghost story.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-orphanage28dec28,0,6917117.story?coll=cl-mreview</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This Spanish supernatural thriller begins interestingly and finishes intriguingly. But what lies between drags because the film lacks a driving story line.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/film/reviews/article_display.jsp?JSESSIONID=zQDXH0pGLNp3LLJ0WjGwm1DhG6yqbDHr3fGq2hBL9h0nCsdbYLx2!-1585743728&amp;&amp;rid=10387</url>
         <critic>Richard James Havis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Orphanage, a diverting, overwrought ghost story from Spain, relies on basic and durable horror movie techniques.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2007/12/28/movies/28orph.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Orphanage is a careful, elegant work that looks a little rough around the edges; it was shot largely with natural light and employs minimal special effects.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2007/12/28/orphanage/</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>There’s not really a bogeyman in The Orphanage and not much blood; just insane intensity and a building sense of bad vibes.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film/superior-mother-the-orphanage/17905/</url>
         <critic>Mark Olsen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Orphanage's joys come from the experiential: Bayona's cultured technical skills, including some phenomenal sound design, and sustained anxiety. It's about as healthy as junk food gets.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/moviereviews/4337/the-orphanage.html</url>
         <critic>Aaron Hillis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's worth a look, even taking into consideration the lack of zombies.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=10478</url>
         <critic>Pete Vonder Haar</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>You may see The Orphanage for what it is, an enjoyable contraption, without believing a bit of it.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB119939738464265817.html</url>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Ultimately the composition comes off as both overplayed and underdone.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A574800</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A combination ghost and shaggy dog story that is so well-made and acted you can nearly overlook its murky, unsatisfying ending.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2007/12/28/2007-12-28_spains_orphanage_has_phantom_end.html</url>
         <critic>Jack Mathews</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>