<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Page Turner, The</name>
   <company>Tartan USA</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Denis Dercourt</author>
      <author>Jacques Sotty</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Denis Dercourt</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>France</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Catherine Frot</actor>
      <actor>Déborah François</actor>
      <actor>Pascal Greggory</actor>
      <actor>Xavier De Guillebon</actor>
      <actor>Christine Citti</actor>
      <actor>Clotilde Mollet</actor>
      <actor>Jacques Bonnaffé</actor>
      <actor>Antoine Martynciow</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>March 23, 2007</release_date>
   <running_time>85</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film flows like a sinister and unsettling piece of music, from gripping overture to the tightly orchestrated movements to the unforgettable coda.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?tvobjectid=286987&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The secret of the film's success is performance, performance, performance.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/RTGAM.20070406.wpage06/BNStory/Entertainment/home</url>
         <critic>Kamal AL-Solaylee</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A little too neat, and self-consciously vague at the end. But it's fascinating to observe and try to interpret François' mysterious smile as she eyes her boss.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/cinema/the_page_turner</url>
         <critic>Noel Murray</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Director and co-writer Denis Dercourt infuses Melanie's calculating seduction of the family with a sense of genuine menace. You will not be bored.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/2007/03/23/2007-03-23_short_takes_bitesize_reviews.html</url>
         <critic>Jack Mathews</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Dercourt, a very fine filmmaker, is a musician himself, a music teacher and one-time solo viola player with the French Symphony Orchestra. And he directs, with a musician's precision and an insider's sly wit, the world of classical music performance.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-070330-movies-review-page,0,7625332.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Wilmington</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though this film is as formal and predetermined as a carved palace of ice, it builds interest through the strong performances of its pair of costars, the veteran Catherine Frot and relative newcomer Deborah Francois.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/printedition/calendar/cl-et-page30mar30,0,2841260.story</url>
         <critic>Kenneth Turan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What The Page Turner lacks in scale and ambition, it makes up for in precision. It's a small French delicacy, tart, acerbic and cynical, that focuses on three or four characters and yet manages to bring them and their dilemmas to vivid life.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1132148&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Stephen Hunter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Scripter-helmer Denis Dercourt's sixth feature is spare but classy, with an impressively controlled perf by Deborah Francois (the young mother in the Dardenne Bros.' "L'enfant") opposite popular and spot-on vet Catherine Frot.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=features2006&amp;content=jump&amp;jump=review&amp;dept=cannes&amp;nav=RCannes&amp;articleid=VE1117930553&amp;cs=1&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>Lisa Nesselson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Anyone who remembers "The Hand That Rocks the Cradle" will see the instruments of revenge laid out like cutlery in a slasher movie's kitchen, and Dercourt's overbright visual scheme aims for a Michael Haneke–esque bourgeois chill that comes off instead as curiously bloodless.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0712,ridley,76153,20.html</url>
         <critic>Jim Ridley</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a fine example of the excellence of French genre film right now: A dark tale of revenge with an inscrutable heart, ice in its veins and an electric undercurrent of eroticism, it also might be the best-photographed picture I've seen so far this year.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2007/03/22/btm/index2.html</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A revenge fantasy fit for a Seventies arthouse theatre: There are no knives or armies of kung-fu acrobats, no torture scenes involving rusty pliers; there's only a creeping malevolence quietly wreaking havoc on an otherwise normal bourgeois family.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A477102</url>
         <critic>Josh Rosenblatt</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A would-be psychological thriller with next to no psychology and shivers instead of thrills, The Page Turner is a nervous-making, lightly amusing vengeance story that owes an obvious debt to Claude Chabrol.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2007/03/23/movies/23page.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>Manohla Dargis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though The Page Turner clearly aims for ambiguity of meaning, you'd have to be blind, or deaf to the strenuously long-faced score, to miss the signs and portents that keep piling up in this dispiritingly transparent movie, which brandishes its foregone conclusion 20 minutes in.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film/single-white-wacko/16007/</url>
         <critic>Ella Taylor</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This premise may sound all right on paper, but on-screen it doesn't really wash: if the girl had been half as committed to music as she now is to revenge, she would have overcome her disappointment.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/30510_PAGE_TURNER.html</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A big fizzle.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/04/06/DDG88P2PAM1.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The stakes in this story seem too low to justify its audience’s attention. If The Page Turner were a novel, it would hardly be a page turner. Why should we hold films to a lower standard?</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=10192</url>
         <critic>Michael Hardy</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>