<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Phat Girlz</name>
   <company>Fox Searchlight Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Comedy</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Nnegest Likké</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Nnegest Likké</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>USA</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>the hilarious Mo&amp;#039;Nique as Jazmin Biltmore</actor>
      <actor>a smart-mouthed aspiring fashion designer</actor>
      <actor>Phat Girlz is an edgy comedy about two frustrated plus-size women obsessed with their weight while struggling to find love  acceptance in a world full of hot bodied bases. The Phat Girlz are thrown a major curve ball when the men of their dreams who come from a culture where big is better.  (Fox Searchlight)</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>April 7, 2006</release_date>
   <running_time>99</running_time>
   <rating>PG-13</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Clumsily directed yet entertainingly written by Oakland native Nnegest Likké, Phat Girlz is like "Rocky" with cellulite. Or maybe "Pretty Woman" without all the bony butts. It has a lot of heart and soul, but it's almost never mean-spirited.</snippet>
         <url>http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2006/04/07/DDG57I442Q9.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Peter Hartlaub</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This is a disarming and, in its own way, delightful vehicle for its star and executive producer, the comedian and actress Mo'Nique. Who could hate this movie?</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/ae/movies/articles/2006/04/08/in_phat_girlz_empowerment_is_entertaining/</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The plus-size personality of comic actress Mo'Nique fills the screen in Phat Girlz, a sweet, if thinly plotted tale.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/04-08-2006/front/story/407099p-344535c.html</url>
         <critic>Robert Dominguez</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Likké should be applauded for tackling a subject that's bristling with sociopolitical thorns and that raises some provocative questions, particularly about what we find attractive in other people and why.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-phat10apr10,0,6903138.story?coll=cl-mreview</url>
         <critic>John Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The humor's vulgar and the plot feeble, but this is a cut above the gross-out comedies aimed at male teens, and its heroine and her gal pals keep the high jinks amiable.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/29573_PHAT_GIRLZ.html</url>
         <critic>Andrea Gronvall</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>While it's a pleasure to watch the likeable Johnson open up and come out of her shell, Phat Girlz belongs to Mo'Nique, a grating, belligerent woman who alternates self-deprecating fat jokes with drama-queen meltdowns and simpering pleas for acceptance. Save it for the talk-show circuit, please.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/47314</url>
         <critic>Scott Tobias</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Mo’Nique's character here is so underwritten that the actress doesn't get a chance to really capitalize on her extra screen-time. Her sassy forte may be talking so straight-up she sounds crazy, but she seems a little advanced to be doing "yo mamma" jokes.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film-reviews/film-reviews/13071/</url>
         <critic>Mark Olsen</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Mo'Nique, a vet standup and sitcom performer whose sassy, brassy shtick isn't nearly enough to support material this insubstantial.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117930186?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1</url>
         <critic>Joe Leydon</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Barely written and stiffly directed.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2006/04/08/movies/08phat.html</url>
         <critic>Nathan Lee</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If it weren't for Mo'Nique's fresh, appealing screen presence, Phat Girlz would fall flat.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20060410.PHAT10/TPStory/TPEntertainment/</url>
         <critic>Jennie Punter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The writing is rudimentary and the direction often awkward, but Mo'Nique would confound a veteran director.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr/reviews/review_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1002315031</url>
         <critic>Kirk Honeycutt</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Lackluster dialogue, ludicrously unbelievable storyline, and the fact that the entire film looks and sounds like it was shot on a camcorder mean nobody outside of the studio’s target demographic is likely to check this out.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=8897</url>
         <critic>Pete Vonder Haar</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Even Mo'Nique's outsize presence isn't enough to make ancient gags about stuck-up popular girls or about voluptuous vultures clearing a whole buffet table in one fell swoop funny.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.tvguide.com/movies/database/Movie-Review.asp?MI=46835</url>
         <critic>Maitland McDonagh</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film is amateurishly directed and sluggishly paced with an anorexic plot. Even the photography, sound and costumes are substandard.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/movies/62123.htm</url>
         <critic>Kyle Smith</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Jazmin's so fat that the movie reduces her to a single discernible characteristic, which is a telltale mark of many a wholly awful comedy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/review/movie/0,6115,1182908_1_0_,00.html</url>
         <critic>Gregory Kirschling</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A dish of empty calories.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A352438</url>
         <critic>Marjorie Baumgarten</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>