<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Science of Sleep, The</name>
   <company>Warner Independent Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Comedy</genre>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Fantasy</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
      <genre>Romance</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Michel Gondry</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Michel Gondry</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>France</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Gael García Bernal</actor>
      <actor>Charlotte Gainsbourg</actor>
      <actor>Alain Chabat</actor>
      <actor>Miou-Miou</actor>
      <actor>Emma de Caunes</actor>
      <actor>Aurélia Petit</actor>
      <actor>Sacha Bourdo</actor>
      <actor>Pierre Vaneck</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>September 22, 2006</release_date>
   <running_time>105</running_time>
   <rating>R</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>An indie version of Gondry's "Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind," albeit with none of the star power, a quarter of the budget, half the angst, and twice the charm.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/53178</url>
         <critic>Tasha Robinson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's not likely you'll see a film more visually exhilarating until, well, Gondry's next.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.premiere.com/article.asp?section_id=2&amp;article_id=3078</url>
         <critic>Glenn Kenny</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Bernal continues to demonstrate an impressive range; the character requires the normally laid-back actor to be a wild ball of energy, and he's more than up to the challenge. His performance is hilarious, heartfelt and more than a little creepy, which could also be said about the movie itself.</snippet>
         <url>http://tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?tvobjectid=283420&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Ethan Alter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This scruffy, unkempt tale lacks the narrative satisfaction of Kaufman's dramatic design, but between the chaotic zigs and creative jags, it proclaims its own kind of messy authenticity and a bittersweet beauty.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/285996_sleep22q.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This fascinating and occasionally transporting film never quite transforms into something really great.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1158782159258810.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>Shawn Levy</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Very difficult to characterize and that's why I like it. The best I can do is to call it a sunny tragedy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2006/0922/p14s01-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's rare for young actors to exude as much charisma and charm as Gainsbourg and García Bernal.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/printedition/calendar/cl-et-sleep22sep22,0,6135363.story</url>
         <critic>Carina Chocano</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>To me, the movie feels like a small but ingeniously crafted gift.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.slate.com/id/2150155</url>
         <critic>Dana Stevens</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Science of Sleep truly has to be seen to be believed.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.filmthreat.com/index.php?section=reviews&amp;Id=8438</url>
         <critic>Sally Foster</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sweet, crazy, and tinged with sadness, Michel Gondry's new feature The Science of Sleep is a wondrous concoction.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0638,hoberman,74497,20.html</url>
         <critic>J. Hoberman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>For the soul of Gondry's work, it seems to me, is neither its soaring flights of visual fancy nor its sometimes crude slapstick, but rather its pained understanding of a generation hopelessly tongue-tied when it comes to matters of the heart.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film-reviews/film-reviews/14533/</url>
         <critic>Scott Foundas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>No one who sees it will confuse it with anything else. Fans of Gondry's DIY low-tech aesthetic, which he blends, as always, with exceptionally sophisticated animation techniques, will adore it.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2006/09/21/btm/index.html</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Gondry is a soft surrealist without much of a sociopolitical agenda, closer to Dr. Seuss than Luis Buñuel,</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/critic.html#30375</url>
         <critic>Jonathan Rosenbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It suffers occasionally from self-consciousness and over-indulgence in its own oddity, but Gondry’s grasp of emotion and visuals is enchanting. Even if he seems several sandwiches short of a picnic.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.empireonline.com/reviews/review.asp?FID=133623</url>
         <critic>Oliver Richards</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Never intends to be deeper than a magician's hat, and its wonderfully low-tech stop-motion technique is not only a nod to Czech animator Jan Svankmajer but a tacit rebuke to computer-graphics-heavy fantasies such as "The Chronicles of Narnia" or the "Lord of the Rings" trilogy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1105145&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Desson Thomson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>I think it's a mess, but - and this is a major caveat - an endearing, beautiful, hopelessly honest mess that's supported by a pair of performances so unnaturally natural that they draw you in and clutch you, struggling, to their flipping, flopping hearts.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A403883</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This pop-up book of a film is an ideal arrangement between director and star.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=8892</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The title is all that's boring about director Michel Gondry's latest mind bender, as trippy as LSD.</snippet>
         <url>http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2006/09/22/DDGUAL9CUD1.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Ruthe Stein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The look of the film is dazzling, even hallucinatory, and the concept is beyond quirky as conceived by Gondry, a talented visual stylist, in his first film based on his own script. The story is compelling, unconventional and diverting in its blurring of reality and fantasy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.usatoday.com/life/movies/reviews/2006-09-21-review-science-confetti_x.htm</url>
         <critic>Claudia Puig</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Unlike Gondry's previous features, Human Nature and Eternal Sunshine, Science lacks the sturdy armature of a Charlie Kaufman screenplay to support its eccentricities. The flood of delight in the film's first 90 minutes slowed to a trickle and, finally, a drip.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.philly.com/entertainment/ui/philly/movie.html?id=673031&amp;reviewId=21528</url>
         <critic>Carrie Rickey</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It only works about half the time, but it's an interesting half.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-060929-movies-review-science,0,4057764.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Wilmington</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Fusing animation and live action with a series of outrageous props, Gondry veers dangerously close to being precious. But make no mistake: Gondry's hallucinatory brilliance holds you in thrall.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.rollingstone.com/reviews/movie/9144761/review/11544971/the_science_of_sleep</url>
         <critic>Peter Travers</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>So while The Science of Sleep may not, in the end, be terribly deep, it is undoubtedly -- and deeply -- refreshing.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2006/09/22/movies/22slee.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>With Mexican star Gael Garcia Bernal energetically playing a vulnerable graphic artist with a hyperactive imagination and little confidence with women, picture has an overriding quality of sweetness that will prove endearing to audiences, especially younger females.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=features2006&amp;content=jump&amp;jump=review&amp;head=berlin&amp;nav=RBerlin&amp;articleid=VE1117929332&amp;cs=1&amp;s=h&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>Todd McCarthy</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Science of Sleep is like a weird dream that tugs at the memory throughout the day with its intriguing, misshapen pieces.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/review/movie/0,6115,1537077_1_0_,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The result is a charming, inventive, ambitious, surreal mess.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/454810p-382573c.html</url>
         <critic>Jack Mathews</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's this edge that saves The Science of Sleep from its own whimsy.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20060922.SLEEP22/TPStory/TPEntertainment/Movies/</url>
         <critic>Jason McBride</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Watching it is like being the only non-stoned person in the room as someone tells a long, long story.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/entertainment/movies/tale_on_sleeping__fruity__could_be_bedder_movies_kyle_smith.htm</url>
         <critic>Kyle Smith</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Certainly pleasant, and occasionally endearing, but it's also strangely empty and unsatisfying, like hearing about someone else's wild dream: You can appreciate the details, but you don't really care how it turns out.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.miami.com/entertainment/ui/miami/movie.html?id=673031&amp;reviewId=21523</url>
         <critic>Rene Rodriguez</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What "Eternal Sunshine" did with magic and whimsy, The Science of Sleep accomplishes with confusion and pretentiousness.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.reelviews.net/movies/s/science_sleep.html</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A frantic and funny diversion, but it pales and tires before its time is up. It doesn't know the meaning of enough.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newyorker.com/critics/cinema/?060925crci_cinema</url>
         <critic>Anthony Lane</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The Science of Sleep transports you, but it strands you, too. Apart from the time-machine bit and two or three other daft exchanges, Gondry’s scenes tend to circle around the same drain: the hero’s insufferable narcissism.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/21366/index.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>You have to identify pretty strongly with suffering artistes to find anything to root for in The Science of Sleep.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/bal-to.science29sep29,0,2591943.story?coll=bal-artslife-movies</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>