<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Sophie Scholl: The Final Days</name>
   <company>Zeitgeist Films</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
      <genre>War</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Fred Breinersdorfer</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Marc Rothemund</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Germany</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Julia Jentsch</actor>
      <actor>Fabian Hinrichs</actor>
      <actor>Gerald Alexer Held</actor>
      <actor>Johanna Gastdorf</actor>
      <actor>André Hennicke</actor>
      <actor>Florian Stetter</actor>
      <actor>Johannes Suhm</actor>
      <actor>Maximilian Brückner</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>February 17, 2006</release_date>
   <running_time>117</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Throughout, Sophie exhibits the quality common to all of history's great martyrs, a preternatural calmness that perseveres despite (or perhaps because of) the inevitability of her doom.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/114548733660490.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>Marc Mohan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's an authentic, harrowing tale of heroism.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/bal-to.sophie21apr21,0,2251592.story?coll=bal-artslife-movies</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl plods along inexorably, one step after another, to its grim, sad end. It's almost unbearable.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A365836</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film is a shattering experience fueled by Jentsch's electrifying performance.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.tvguide.com/movies/database/ShowMovie.asp?MI=46743</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>While the film doesn't dig deep, or hit particularly hard, it neatly achieves its modest goals: presenting a real-life heroine in real-life terms. A film this fictionalized rarely feels this much like fact.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/45701</url>
         <critic>Tasha Robinson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Rothemund's use of the recorded testimony, while it gives his film a startling veracity, also limits his imagination. It prevents him from delving too deeply into the psychology of these activists.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2006/0224/p11s02-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Julia Jentsch strong and graceful, quiet knockout of a performance is the film's most potent weapon.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-sophie24feb24,0,2601983.story</url>
         <critic>Kenneth Turan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl: The Final Days may sound like a history lesson, but don't be fooled. It's a horror film.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.newyorker.com/critics/cinema/?060227crci_cinema</url>
         <critic>Anthony Lane</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's a crisply made, absorbing human drama that frames its moral confrontation between good and evil in universal terms.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2006/02/16/btm/index.html</url>
         <critic>Andrew O&amp;#039;Hehir</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Rock solid performances by up-and-coming German actress Julia Jentsch as Sophie and Alexander Held ("Downfall") as Mohr along with an excellent cast of supporting players insure that no one mistakes this for a lifeless docu-drama.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr/reviews/review_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1000799840</url>
         <critic>Kirk Honeycutt</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>An ace performance by 26-year-old Julia Jentsch ("The Edukators," "Snowland"), as the quietly determined Munich student who was beheaded for distributing counter-propaganda leaflets in 1943, gives pic a focused dramatic power.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/ac2006_review/VE1117926208?nav=reviews&amp;categoryid=1986&amp;cs=</url>
         <critic>Derek Elley</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A life so tragically and quickly extinguished presents maudlin temptations, but director Marc Rothemund ably resists them. His gripping, moving film focuses on a breathtakingly brief five-day period.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0607,camhi,72189,20.html</url>
         <critic>Leslie Camhi</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This gripping true story, directed in a cool, semi-documentary style by the German filmmaker Marc Rothemund from a screenplay by Fred Breinersdorfer, challenges you to gauge your own courage and strength of character should you find yourself in similar circumstances.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2006/02/17/movies/17soph.html</url>
         <critic>Stephen Holden</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Though we know the story's final outcome, the trial scene and its aftermath are no less shocking and affecting.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.dallasobserver.com/Issues/2006-04-06/film/film4.html</url>
         <critic>Jean Oppenheimer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Julia Jentsch offers a brilliant example of what actors call "not playing the ending," and the awful suspense of the piece is watching as she realizes, in increments, that this is all much worse than she thought.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20060407.SOPHIE07/TPStory/TPEntertainment/</url>
         <critic>Liam Lacey</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Everything about Sophie Scholl screams "martyr" and "saint." Jentsch will have none of it. Hers is a performance of supreme emotional control, yet clear emotional fire. The actress makes the icon human.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-060331-movies-review-sophie,0,4686658.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film holds us rapt not through narrative suspense but through the eerie and demanding spectacle of profound moral courage, of a powerless good person in collision with absolute evil.</snippet>
         <url>http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2006/03/03/DDGA1HHC971.DTL</url>
         <critic>Mick LaSalle</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Rothemund gives us his sophisticated filmmaking only in the finale, which is devastating in its briskness and fury.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=8595</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The orderly and clean drama is more like theater than history come to life.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/263246_limited17.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The effect of this scene is so powerful that I leaned forward like a jury member, wanting her to get away with it so I could find her innocent.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.rogerebert.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20060330/REVIEWS/60323005/1023</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl is a powerful story. But it's a little annoying how men become beside the point when the focus is on emotion. Sophie did no more or less than her brother, but he's ignored for nearly all of the movie because it's easier to stir up compassion - it's easier to manipulate the audience - when the subject is a woman.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/movies/63692.htm</url>
         <critic>Kyle Smith</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl has a certain quiet dignity that wins its audience popularity honestly.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/review/movie/0,6115,1162032_1_0_,00.html</url>
         <critic>Lisa Schwarzbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl is the subject of a feature film that has earned an Oscar nomination for a Germany she would have loved to live in.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/394257p-334143c.html</url>
         <critic>Jack Mathews</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The script is so intellectualized that I couldn't help feeling I was witnessing not two complex people locked in struggle, but the opposed souls (and classes) of Germany: Sophie, emblem of the cultured, tolerant and enlightened humanism of the middle classes duking it out with Mohr, resentful member of a disenfranchised proletariat from whose ranks sprang Hitler's most loyal quislings.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film/12750/thug-lives/</url>
         <critic>Ella Taylor</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Modest in scale but formidable in its impact.</snippet>
         <url/>
         <critic>Joe Morgenstern</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sophie Scholl is not as devastatingly moving as "The White Rose," but it, too, evokes awe in lesser beings.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tnr.com/doc.mhtml?i=20060227&amp;s=kauffmann022706</url>
         <critic>Stanley Kauffmann</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Andre Hennicke is particularly chilling as the yappy mad dog judge who sends them to death.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1114996&amp;lat=200.0&amp;lon=200.0&amp;displaySearchLocation=&amp;nm=1&amp;categories=Movies</url>
         <critic>Stephen Hunter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>After she's forced to confess, director Marc Rothemund doesn't have much to do but marvel at her heroic defiance, and the film is overtaken by its talkiness, claustrophobia, and polarized morality.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/29432_SOPHIE_SCHOLL_THE_FINAL_DAYS_SOPHIE_SCHOLL_DIE_LETZTEN_TAGE.html</url>
         <critic>J.R. Jones</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Powerfully rendered in every respect - and another testament to how bad the Nazis are for drama.</snippet>
         <url>http://newyorkmetro.com/movies/reviews/15903/</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>For most U.S. audiences, Sophie Scholl: The Final Days, an Academy Award nominee for best foreign language film, is going to feel more like a history lesson than a movie.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.miami.com/entertainment/ui/miami/movie.html?id=473285&amp;reviewId=20392</url>
         <critic>Connie Ogle</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>