<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Tears of the Black Tiger</name>
   <company>Magnolia Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Action</genre>
      <genre>Comedy</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Wisit Sasanatieng</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Wisit Sasanatieng</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Thailand</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Chartchai Ngamsan</actor>
      <actor>Suwinit Panjamawat</actor>
      <actor>Stella Malucchi</actor>
      <actor>Supakorn Kitsuwon</actor>
      <actor>Arawat Ruangvuth</actor>
      <actor>Sombat Metanee</actor>
      <actor>Pairoj Jaisingha</actor>
      <actor>Naiyana Sheewanun</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>January 12, 2007</release_date>
   <running_time>113</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>What do you get when you mix a Douglas Sirk melodrama with a Sergio Leone Western? Tears of the Black Tiger, a high-camp Western from, of all places, Thailand.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/01122007/entertainment/movies/campy_western_is_thai_die_for_movies_v_a__musetto.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A parody of and winking homage to the history of Thai melodrama, Wisit Sasanatieng's uproarious filmmaking debut exuberantly combines pop and kitsch with a wholesome belief in the thrills of bad art.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=9887</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It has a tendency to overextend its outrageous arias, but this pop-art confection both spoofs and celebrates the crazy conventions of movie melodramas and genre cinema with pure affection.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/305666_limited02.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It is astonishing to realize that the highly confident Tears of the Black Tiger marks the directorial debut of Sasanatieng, after having written two movies hugely successful in Thailand, yet in truth he belongs to a long line of first-rate filmmakers who understand the wisdom of taking big chances the first time at bat.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/printedition/calendar/cl-et-tiger2mar02,0,393499.story</url>
         <critic>Kevin Thomas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Written and directed by Wisit Sasanatieng, a commercial director making his first feature film, Tears of the Black Tiger is a technical and aesthetic marvel.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.slate.com/id/2157490/fr/flyout</url>
         <critic>Dana Stevens</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Nothing is too crazed, corny, or freakishly florid for Tears of the Black Tiger. The debut of writer-director Wisit Sasanatieng is a delightfully unabashed affair, conceived in such good, giddy spirits it might have been called "Blissfully Yours."</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0702,lee,75505,20.html</url>
         <critic>Nathan Lee</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>If Tears is indeed too weird to take America by storm – Miramax bought the film after Cannes and shelved it until it is now being released by Magnolia – it should neither be considered a cult item, approachable only to film nerds (though they will appreciate it best).</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A446131</url>
         <critic>Marrit Ingman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The result is something so old it's new, so corny it's funny. And while Tears of the Black Tiger is nothing more than entertaining, at least it's that.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-070302-movies-review-tiger,0,5044191.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Wilmington</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie is never going to have broad appeal. Though Sasanatieng makes a few swings at real poignancy--which don't really connect--mostly this is the kind of relentlessly postmodern "fun" best served in small portions, and preferably on dessert plates.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/57477</url>
         <critic>Noel Murray</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Director Wisit Sasanatieng uses every trick imaginable to create surreal postmodern nostalgia. Has he wound up with pure camp, or a cult classic? As he clearly understands, the best B-movies are both.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/488073p-410820c.html</url>
         <critic>Elizabeth Weitzman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A delirious fever dream of pulp-western conventions by way of 1950s Hollywood melodrama, Thai filmmaker Wisit Sasanatieng surreal oddity unfolds in heavily manipulated colors so rich they seem ready to leap off the screen, punctuated by spasms of over-ripe dialogue, floridly dramatic songs and maniacal villainous laughter.</snippet>
         <url>http://tvguide.com/detail/movie.aspx?tvobjectid=285499&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Maitland McDonagh</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This is a scrapbook, a happy jumble, of many of the things we instinctively respond to in movies: color, shape, sound and movement, all intensified by heightened emotion.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.salon.com/ent/movies/review/2007/01/12/tears/index.html</url>
         <critic>Stephanie Zacharek</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The intoxicating madness of Tears of the Black Tiger is in the end too willed, too deliberate, to be entirely divine.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2007/01/12/movies/12tige.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A jaw-dropper: a delirium-inducing crash course in international trash.</snippet>
         <url>http://nymag.com/movies/reviews/26289/index.html</url>
         <critic>David Edelstein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Its giddy stylistics include extravagant use of color and rapid montage, which are said to be a direct homage to legendary Thai independent Ratana Pestonji.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/31166_TEARS_OF_THE_BLACK_TIGER_FAH_TALAI_JONE.html</url>
         <critic>Jonathan Rosenbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie alternates between cornball and ridiculous, and the frequent violence is extremely bloody if stylized. Love it or hate it, and I'm not sure which applies to me, you've never seen and never will see anything quite like Tears of the Black Tiger.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1133182&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>Stephen Hunter</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie is one big in-joke. It's watchable, but eventually wears you down with its over-the-top cleverness.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/02/09/DDG0GO0LU11.DTL#flick2</url>
         <critic>Ruthe Stein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Fun, if finally too silly.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117788680.html?categoryid=31&amp;cs=1</url>
         <critic>Ken Eisner</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A few more films like Tears of the Black Tiger, and kitsch will be on its way to having a bad name.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,20008795,00.html</url>
         <critic>Owen Gleiberman</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>