<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Three Times</name>
   <company>IFC Films</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
      <genre>Foreign</genre>
      <genre>Romance</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>T&amp;#039;ien-wen Chu</author>
      <author>Hsiao-hsien Hou</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Hsiao-hsien Hou</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Taiwan</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Chen Chang</actor>
      <actor>Qi Shu</actor>
      <actor>Mei Di</actor>
      <actor>Su-jen Liao</actor>
      <actor>Fang Mei</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>April 26, 2006</release_date>
   <running_time>120</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>It's simply one of the most beautiful films he's (Hou Hsiao Hsien) made to date.</snippet>
         <url>http://online.tvguide.com/newsearch/detail.aspx?id=46904&amp;sourcetype=m&amp;progseriesparentid=0&amp;tvobjectid=0&amp;keyword=&amp;more=ucmoviereview</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Three Times is great cinema, pop romance that carries a special charge.</snippet>
         <url>http://metromix.chicagotribune.com/movies/mmx-060623-movies-review-three,0,5236200.story?coll=mmx-movies_top_heds</url>
         <critic>Michael Wilmington</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Three Times, one of the peaks of his (Hou Hsiao-hsien) career, may be your last chance to see his work inside a movie theater.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.chicagoreader.com/features/stories/moviereviews/060623/</url>
         <critic>Jonathan Rosenbaum</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Three varieties of love: unfulfilled, mercenary, meaningless. All photographed with such visual beauty that watching the movie is like holding your breath so the butterfly won’t stir.</snippet>
         <url>http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20060622/REVIEWS/60620004</url>
         <critic>Roger Ebert</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>One of the best films of the year.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2006/07/07/DDGP1JQ9F31.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>G. Allen Johnson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The style is pure Hou: richly textured atmosphere, tiptoeing camerawork and long, languorous takes of scenes full of privileged moments of human activity.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/277461_limited14.html</url>
         <critic>Sean Axmaker</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>I urge you to see the ineffably beautiful Three Times however you can, lest you go on thinking that Hou's greatness is merely the supposition of obscurantist critics intent on reserving their highest praise for those films that nobody else can actually see.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.laweekly.com/film+tv/film/as-times-goes-by/13490/</url>
         <critic>Scott Foundas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Finds Taiwanese master Hou Hsiao-hsien at his most intimate and romantic. The deceptive simplicity of these vignettes, written by Chu Tien-wen, throws into relief Hou's formidable storytelling strengths and visual acuity - his way with actors, his subtlety and expressiveness.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/cl-et-three12may12,0,5553105.story</url>
         <critic>Kevin Thomas</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Politics in Three Times is as subtle as the stories being told. The film is probably too slow, too silent and too long for most audiences. But look beyond the quietness, and you'll discover a three-gem jewel.</snippet>
         <url>http://ae.miami.com/entertainment/ui/miami/movie.html?id=595470&amp;reviewId=20825</url>
         <critic>Marta Barber</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Another triumph of modesty from a master who deserves real, paying audiences, not just the adoration of besotted film critics.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=9014</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>In these three potent miniatures, Hou Hsiao-hsien suggests that time passes differently when you're deeply in love. He captures the mystical quality of that time on film, making us feel as if we're living in it, rather than simply watching it.</snippet>
         <url>http://dir.salon.com/story/ent/movies/review/2005/10/05/three_times/index.html?CP=IMD&amp;DN=110</url>
         <critic>Stephanie Zacharek</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Taiwanese director Hou Hsiao-hsien's hypnotically beautiful cinematic trilogy Three Times doesn't just illuminate faces and objects; it seems to fill them up, as if they were lighted from within.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies2.nytimes.com/2006/04/26/movies/26thre.html</url>
         <critic>Manohla Dargis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Anchored by the performance of Shu Qi, who has come a long way from her days as a nudie pin-up. She's a first-rate actress.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/movies/65056.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A sampler of novella-length films set in three different time periods and starring the same two actors, Hou Hsiao-hsien's Three Times resembles one of those delicate trios served at fine restaurants, each a fresh interpretation of a common ingredient.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.avclub.com/content/node/47879</url>
         <critic>Scott Tobias</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A lyrical, subtle, chaste and nearly wordless romance.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/movies/moviereviews/story/412761p-348937c.html</url>
         <critic>Jami Bernard</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Do Hou's films deserve to be seen? Absolutely, if only to end the myth that they're too perfect for this world.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.ew.com/ew/article/review/movie/0,6115,1190477_1_0_,00.html</url>
         <critic>Owen Gleiberman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>My first impression of Three Times was that it was high middling Hou--conceptually bold but unevenly executed. The movie's implicit themes of time travel, eternal recurrence, and the transmigration of souls seemed as muddied by the director's devotion to Shu as they were dissipated in the confusion of the final present-day section. But Three Times improves on a second viewing.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0617,hoberman,72990,20.html</url>
         <critic>J. Hoberman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Less accessible than recent "Cafe Lumiere," picture will appeal strongly to fans.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/review/VE1117927202?categoryid=1929&amp;cs=1&amp;s=h&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>Jay Weissberg</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Features minimal dialogue. It is mostly about mood and images, and it moves at a glacial pace.</snippet>
         <url>http://movie-reviews.colossus.net/movies/t/three_times.html</url>
         <critic>James Berardinelli</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Three Times offers a careful examination of the changing ways people have reacted to each other during the past 100 years. As such, it's an interesting essay but certainly a minor work from a master.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr/reviews/review_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1001221698</url>
         <critic>Richard James Havis</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The film's trouble is in what happens in each section: not enough. Once the atmosphere of each period is established, the story is too weak to interest--and the characterizations are too thin to compensate.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tnr.com/doc.mhtml?i=20060501&amp;s=kauffmann050106</url>
         <critic>Stanley Kauffmann</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The first section of Three Times is fabulous; the second is fascinating if remote; and the third a jangly, modernist mess.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1121322&amp;lat=200.0&amp;lon=200.0&amp;displaySearchLocation=&amp;nm=1&amp;categories=Movies</url>
         <critic>Stephen Hunter</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>