<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<movie>
   <name>Year My Parents Went on Vacation, The</name>
   <company>City Lights Pictures</company>
   <genres>
      <genre>Drama</genre>
   </genres>
   <authors>
      <author>Cao Hamburger</author>
   </authors>
   <directors>
      <director>Cao Hamburger</director>
   </directors>
   <origins>
      <origin>Brazil</origin>
   </origins>
   <actors>
      <actor>Michel Joelsas</actor>
      <actor>Daniela Piepszyk</actor>
      <actor>Liliana Castro</actor>
   </actors>
   <release_date>February 15, 2008</release_date>
   <running_time>110</running_time>
   <rating>Not</rating>
   <reviews>
      <review>
         <snippet>Most political films involving children are vicious or sentimental. The Year My Parents Went on Vacation, set in 1970 when Brazil was under the military dictatorship of General Emilio Medici, is neither.</snippet>
         <url>http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/movies/358560_parents11q.html</url>
         <critic>Bill White</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Pulls you into a well-observed world and its characters.</snippet>
         <url>http://chicago.metromix.com/movies/movie_review/movie-review-the-year/345200/content</url>
         <critic>Michael Phillips</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A sweet, intelligent little movie.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.oregonlive.com/movies/oregonian/index.ssf?/base/entertainment/1205967362245940.xml&amp;coll=7</url>
         <critic>M. E. Russell</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This sweet, yet unsentimental film is about growing up, losing innocence, and longing for a place, and people, to call home.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.philly.com/inquirer/columnists/steven_rea/20080425_The_Year_My_Parents_Went_on_Vacation____.html</url>
         <critic>Steven Rea</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What makes this film appealingly honest are its details, not its grand events.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.charlotte.com/entertainment/story/605265.html</url>
         <critic>Lawrence Toppman</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The movie is stolen by 11-year-old Daniela Piepszyk as tomboy Hanna, one of Mauro's new friends. She has a face in a million.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.nypost.com/seven/02152008/entertainment/movies/brazilian_flick_a_kick_97666.htm</url>
         <critic>V.A. Musetto</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Hamburger's earnest effort offers interesting perspectives on Jewish life in South America's most populous city as well as the fate of political dissidents during a particularly dark period of Brazil's recent past.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.tvguide.com/movies/year-parents-went/review/292370</url>
         <critic>Ken Fox</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The filmmakers succeed with an unexpected ending. It's as fresh as everything in the movie, which turns out to be about so much more than one youngster's resilience.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2008/02/22/DDE4V5PNE.DTL&amp;type=movies</url>
         <critic>Ruthe Stein</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>It really only comes alive in its shots of people in the neighborhood sitting around their television sets. What we're really talking about here is a problem in scope. In Hamburger's film, the world is no bigger than a cup.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.boston.com/movies/display?display=movie&amp;id=11404</url>
         <critic>Wesley Morris</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Sensitive, delicate and involving.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.variety.com/index.asp?layout=festivals&amp;jump=review&amp;id=2478&amp;reviewid=VE1117932739&amp;cs=1&amp;p=0</url>
         <critic>Deborah Young</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This warmly engaging film benefits from its understated approach (it suggests rather than spells out the political turmoil), and its light, comedic tone never mitigates the drama of the central story.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.villagevoice.com/film/0807,oppenheimer,79095,20.html</url>
         <critic>Jean Oppenheimer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>The performances are charming and convincing, and Mr. Joelsas does a good job of conveying Mauro’s loneliness and confusion as well as his playfulness. The Year My Parents Went on Vacation may not be terribly fresh or original, but its warm, sweet, nostalgic tone is hard to dislike.</snippet>
         <url>http://movies.nytimes.com/2008/02/15/movies/15vaca.html?ref=movies</url>
         <critic>A.O. Scott</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>This nuanced coming-of-age drama by Cao Hamburger exudes warmth without getting mired in nostalgia.</snippet>
         <url>http://onfilm.chicagoreader.com/movies/briefs/32909_YEAR_MY_PARENTS_WENT_ON_VACATION.html</url>
         <critic>Andrea Gronvall</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Generally, this writer-director is too sensitive for his own good. He never lets his boy-hero lose himself fully in his new world - or relinquish hope that his parents will return.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.baltimoresun.com/entertainment/movies/reviews/bal-to.year11apr11,0,3124254.story</url>
         <critic>Michael Sragow</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>Writer-director Cao Hamburger works well with child actors and has a spare, unforced style. But too much of this film is desultory and thin.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.csmonitor.com/2008/0215/p15s01-almo.html</url>
         <critic>Peter Rainer</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>One true gem is Daniela Piepszyk, Mauro's teen neighbor, who is a fireball and the leader of the neighborhood gang of boys. You can't take your eyes off her.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.miamiherald.com/1054/story/418769.html</url>
         <critic>Marta Barber</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A sweet and somber film that works hard to overcome its limitations.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.calendarlive.com/movies/reviews/cl-et-vacation15feb15,0,2162849.story</url>
         <critic>Kenneth Turan</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>What The Year My Parents Went on Vacation seems to be about, in the end, is big-time sport as the opiate of the masses.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/ac2/wp-dyn?node=cityguide/profile&amp;id=1146894&amp;categories=Movies&amp;nm=1</url>
         <critic>John Anderson</critic>
      </review>
      <review>
         <snippet>A curiously unaffecting amalgam of the archetypal coming-of-age tale, here twinned to "outsider" religious overtones (in this case São Paulo's Orthodox Jewish community) and a small but deadly dose of uneasy political melodrama.</snippet>
         <url>http://www.austinchronicle.com/gyrobase/Calendar/Film?Film=oid%3A607603</url>
         <critic>Marc Savlov</critic>
      </review>
   </reviews>
   <summer_release>false</summer_release>
   <christmas_release>false</christmas_release>
   <memorial_release>false</memorial_release>
   <independence_release>false</independence_release>
   <labor_release>false</labor_release>
</movie>